[
    
    {
        "QorL":"Q",
        "question":"In majority of higher animals and plants,_______ and _______ are mutually exclusive events.",
        "options":
        [
            "growth, nutrition",
            "nutrition, consciousness",
            "growth, reproduction",
            "reproduction; consciousness"
        ],
        "correctAns": "growth, reproduction"
    },
    {
        "QorL":"Q",
        "question":"The sum total of all the chemical reactions occurring in our body is known as",
        "options":
        [
            "Metabolism",
            "Growth",
            "Regeneration",
            "reproduction"
        ],
        "correctAns": "Metabolism"
    },
    {
        "QorL":"Q",
        "question":"Which of the following term is used to refer the number of varieties of plants and animals on earth ?",
        "options":
        [
            "Taxonomy",
            "Identification",
            "Biodiversity",
            "Classification"
        ],
        "correctAns": "Biodiversity"
    },
    {
        "QorL":"Q",
        "question":"Which is not a property of living being?",
        "options":
        [
            "Metabolism",
            "Decay",
            "Growth",
            "Reproduction"
        ],
        "correctAns": "Decay"
    },
    {
        "QorL":"Q",
        "question":"A particular plant is strictly seasonal plant. Which one of the following is best suited if it is to be studied in the laboratory?",
        "options":
        [
            "Herbarium",
            "Museum",
            "Botanical garden",
            "Flower exhibition"
        ],
        "correctAns": "Herbarium"
    },
    {
        "QorL":"Q",
        "question":"A group of students found two cockroaches in the classroom. They had a debate whether they are alive or dead. Which life property will help them to do so?",
        "options":
        [
            "Metabolism",
            "Growth",
            "Irritability",
            "Reproduction"
        ],
        "correctAns": "Metabolism"
    },
    {
        "QorL":"Q",
        "question":"Herbarium is a",
        "options":
        [
            "garden where medicinal plants are grown.",
            "garden where herbaceous plants are grown.",
            "dry garden.",
            "chemical to kill plants."
        ],
        "correctAns": "dry garden."
    },
    {
        "QorL":"Q",
        "question":"The famous botanical garden ‘Kew’ is located in",
        "options":
        [
            "England",
            "Lucknow",
            "Berlin",
            "Australia"
        ],
        "correctAns": "England"
    },
    {
        "QorL":"Q",
        "question":"In printed scientific names, only the ________ is capitalized.",
        "options":
        [
            "class",
            "species",
            "genus",
            "family"
        ],
        "correctAns": "genus"
    },
    {
        "QorL":"Q",
        "question":"ICBN stands for",
        "options":
        [
            "International Code of Botanical Nomenclature",
            "International Congress of Biological Names",
            "Indian Code of Botanical Nomenclature",
            "Indian Congress of Biological Names"
        ],
        "correctAns": ""
    }
]